1955년, 뉴욕
해리!
안녕?
여보세요?
해롤드 엔젤입니다
전화번호부 순서대로구요
중간이름은 'R'이죠
뭐라구요?
와인셉
How are you?
와인셉이요?
와인셉 매킨토시?
잠깐, 받아 적죠
Hello!
Yes, this is Harold Angel.
좋아요, 와인셉
와인셉 매킨토시
적었어요
Yes, initial R, like in the phone book.
Excuse me?
Winesap.
물론 이태리인들 속성을 알죠
Herman Winesap,
Winesap & Mackintosh?
변호사라면 더 비싸겠군요
Hold on a second!
물론, 그러죠
망할 녀석
Winesap from Winesap & . . .
Mackintosh. I've got it!
와인셉씨? 해롤드 엔젤이오
Of course I know what an attorney is.
예, 시간은 있소
It's like a lawyer,
only the bills are bigger.
당신친구는 어떻게 되죠?
Sure, I'll hold.
Asshole!
다시 한 번 불러주시오
루이스, 스펠링은요?
Hello, Mr. Winesap? Harold Angel.
사이퍼...좋아요
외국인이오?
Yeah, I could be free.
외국인?
고객이 외국인이오?
Would this be with your firm?
좋아요, 와인셉씨
좀 더 자세히 말해 주겠소?
Gimme that again.
Louis . . . how do you spell that?
아, 좋아요
어딘지 압니다
한참 걸리겠지만 가봐야죠
Cyphre . . . okay.
What is it . . . foreign?
Is your client a foreigner?
Mr. Winesap, could you
give me a few more details?
Okay, I know the place.
It's a long way up, but I can be there.
날 보라, 전해줄 것이로다
할렐루야
날 보라, 제단을 부를 것이로다
날 보라, 재생의 길로 안내하리라
할렐루야
여기에 너희의 왕국이 있노라
오늘 원하노라. 할렐루야
나를 따르라. 나를 따라 지나리라
그래!
오, 할렐루야
당장 하나님의 사랑을 보여주고 싶노라
너희의 마을에 보여주고 싶노라
너희의 마음을 열기를 바라노라
지갑을 열기 바라노라
너희의 불길을 열기바라며
난 그 불길을 얻기 바라노라
그리고 포기하라
순간의 곳으로
내게로 와서 말하라
이런 말을...
난 캐딜락을 샀던 적이 있다
너희가 날 사랑하며 주고 싶은 게
있다면 난 롤스로이스를 타게 되리라
Hallelujah!
Show right now how much you love God!
I want you to show! It's your time!
Open up your hearts
and open up your wallets!
자 노래나 합시다
자, 어서
Open your purses!
Open your pockets!
And give it up! Praise the Lord!
Somebody has been talking about me
엔젤 씨?
허먼 와인셉이오
riding around in a Cadillac.
If you love me and want to give to me,
따라오시겠습니까?
then I should be in a Rolls-Royce!
불행히도 존 목사가 남편의 머리에
총을 쏘게 했답니다
보는 앞에서요
Would you come with me, please?
엔젤씨, 가시죠
An unfortunate husband
of one of Pastor John's flock
took a gun to his head. Most unpleasant.
Mr. Angel? Please?
엔젤씨...
제 고객이신 루이스 사이퍼 씨를
소개해 드리죠
- 안녕, 해리 엔젤이오
- 반갑소, 엔젤씨
자존심 상하게 하고 싶진 않지만...
시작하기 전에 신분확인이
될 만한 게 있을까요?
물론
Allow me to introduce my client,
Monsieur Louis Cyphre.
가지고 있는 게...
어떻소?
Hi, Harry Angel.
- Pleased to meet you, Mr. Angel.
총기소지 허가
I don't want to appear impolite,
개인신상은 없군요
다만 소지한 게 맘에 드는군요
but do you have any l. D.?
- Sure! Here . . .
알아요. 알아
그럼 이제...
How's that?
어떻게 날 알아냈죠?
GU N PERM IT
아마 전화번호부를
뒤졌나 보군요
Nothing personal.
I'm a little over-cautious.
You know how these things are.
- I know. So . . .
보통은 대게...
내 이름이 엔젤이니
첫 글자 A를 본거겠죠
How did you hear about me?
책에는 A부터 시작하니
뒤지다 보면...
- 자니 패이보릿
- 뭐라구요?
자니 패이보릿이란 이름을
기억해 본적 있소?
I guess
you guys just looked in the phone book.
자니란 이름이라...
아뇨, 없어요
- 전혀 모르오?
- 알아야 할 이유라도요?
Usually that's what happens. Because
my name is "Angel", it's under "A" . . .
전쟁 전에 가수였죠
꽤 유명했나봐요
People are lazy.
They see the first name
- 글쎄요, 그러니까 사이피에씨...
- 사이퍼요
and . . .
- Johnny Favorite.
Excuse me?
Do you by chance remember
the name Johnny Favorite?
무척 죄송합니다
사이퍼 씨, 난...
Johnny . . .
No, I don't think so.
보통 이런 일을 해본 적이
없어서인데 난...
You never knew him?
- Am I supposed to?
난 항상 작은 일만 다루었어요
He was a crooner before the war,
quite famous in his way.
교회 일이나 이혼문제...
Well, I tell you, Mr. Cyphre . . .
자연적인 일들만요
운이 좋아 사람들일도 했지만...
하지만 난 모르는 게...
I'm sorry!
가수라던가 유명인 따위 말예요
말 뜻 알겠죠?
I usually don't get involved
- 본명은 리블링이오
- 그건...
in anything very heavy. I usually
handle insurance jobs, divorces,
리블링 역시 몰라요
things of that nature.
나보고 그자를 어쩌라는 거요?
그자가 빚진 거라도 있나요?
If I'm lucky sometimes
I handle people. But I don't know
꼭 그렇진 않지만
난 그의 경력을 도우려는 거요
no crooners
그러니까 당신은...
그의 대리인이오?
or anybody famous.
- His real name was Liebling.
아니, 아니오. 그렇지 않아요
I don't know any Liebling, either.
사이퍼 씨는 계약을 했죠
What do you want from me?
전투에서 그가 죽었다면 갑자기 깨진
달걀과도 같이 잘못이 없죠
Does this man owe you money?
- Not quite.
지금 달걀이
죽은 얘길 하는 거요?
I helped Johnny
at the beginning of his career.
아뇨, 그는 1943년 북 아프리카에
징집됐었죠
You were like . . . his agent?
특수 엔터테인먼트 부대죠
No!
공격을 받아 머리와 얼굴에
중상을 당해 그는...
Nothing so . . .
손상된 거지. 그걸 뭐라더라...
Monsieur Cyphre has a contract.
Certain collateral was to be forfeited
in the event of his death.
- 정신적 쇼크요?
- 정신적 쇼크. 맞아요
- 내가 거절 못할 이유라도요?
- 당신 의무아닌가요, 엔젤씨?
You're talking about a guy that's dead?
- He was drafted in '43,
예, 물론 일할 시간은 있지만...
North Africa.
"Special Entertainment Services".
좀 지저분하고 빌어먹을 일이라서요
내 말씨를 용서하세요
There was an attack,
and his head and face was badly injured.
분명 일도 해내지 못하고 집에
돌아가게 될 겁니다
He had . . .
- Amnesia. I think you call it . . .
전쟁통에 생긴 일이니까
오히려 행운이겠죠
Shell shock.
- Exactly! - I know how that feels.
자니에겐 행운이 아니오
그는 식물인간으로 돌아왔소
Why? Were you in the services?
- I was in for a short time.
그의 친구들이 그를 개인병원으로
이송했어요
But I got a little fucked up.
Excuse me! They shipped me home,
and I missed the whole shebang:
거기서 어떤 치료를 한 것으로
생각되는데...
패이보릿의 변호사의 힘으로
돌아오게 해서...
the war, the medals, everything.
I guess you could say I was lucky.
돈을 지불했다는 정도요
계약서엔 결코 식물인간이란 항목을
쓴 사실이 없다는 걸 아실 겁니다
Johnny wasn't so lucky.
He returned home a zombie.
- 말하세요
- 개인적인 것은 전혀 원치 않지만...
His friends had him transferred
to a private hospital upstate.
다만 자니가 죽었는지 살았는지만
알고 싶을 뿐이오
There was some sort of
radical psychiatric treatment involved.
His lawyers had
the power of attorney
내 사무실에서 확실히
말해둬야 할 게 있다면
to pay the bills, things like that.
But you know how it is.
자니 리블링이
실로 살아있는지 그거요
He remained a vegetable, and my
contract was never honored. - I see.
지난 주말 폽킵시 외곽에
있는 병원에...
I don't want to sound mercenary.
사이퍼 씨와 내가
직접 가서 확인할...
좋은 기회가 있었죠
My only interest in Johnny
is in finding out if he's alive or dead.
직접 조사해 보려고 했었는데...
우린 정보를 놓쳐버렸어요
Each year my office receives a
signed affidavit confirming
찾아다녔군요
그렇소. 사실 난 그런 일에
나서기가 싫었고...
that Johnny Liebling
is indeed among the living.
내 생각엔
당신 같은 분이 오히려...
But last weekend
Monsieur Cyphre and l, just by chance,
차분한 매너가 있다고 생각해서요
were near the clinic in Poughkeepsie.
- 나보고 조사해달란 말이죠?
- 조사해 주시오
We decided to check for ourselves,
but we got misleading information.
좋아요, 그러죠
The run-around!
I didn't want to cause a scene,
I hate any sort of fuss.
어디선가 뵌 것 같은데요
난 모르겠어요
생각 안나요
I thought, perhaps you could
subtly and in a quiet manner . . .
You want me to check it out.
- Check it out!
자니 패이보릿이란 이름을
기억해 본적 있소?
I have a feeling I've met you before.
I don't know, I don't think so.
그의 본명은 리블링이오
다만 자니가 죽었는지 살았는지만
알고 싶을 뿐이오
Do you remember
the name Johnny Favorite?
사라 돗스 하베스트 기념병원
His real name was Liebling.
My only interest in Johnny
is in finding out if he's alive or dead.
프레스 카드
U.S 세관 대행원
국립 보건학회
예
- 도와드릴까요?
- 예
국립 보건학회에서온
해리 캔로이오
무슨 특별한 볼일이라도요?
학회에서 운영하는 일인데 좀
알아볼게 있어요
정신과는 당신들
담당인걸로 아는데
환자 명단을 확인하려구요
May I help you?
- My name is Harry Conroy
예약을 하지 않으면
보여드릴 수 없어요
from the National lnstitute of Health.
그렇긴 하지만 당신이 파일을
조사해 준다면
정확히 알 수 있어요
Is there
anyone in particular you want to see?
토요일엔 누구도 귀찮게
하기 싫어서예요
The lnstitute is conducting a survey
of incurable trauma cases.
좋죠? 고맙소
I understand you have a patient here
fitting that description?
- 환자 이름은요?
- 리블링. 조나단 리블링
잠깐 기다리세요
조사해 보죠
We can't let you see anyone
without an appointment.
I appreciate that,
but maybe you could check the files
지난 주말에 근무했나요?
and make sure I'm on the right track.
아뇨, 쉬는 날이에요
I don't want to bother anybody
unnecessarily.
- 밤에 한 일이 없나요?
- 동생 결혼식이었어요
Okay? Thank you.
What's the name of the patient?
- Liebling, Jonathan Liebling.
리블링씨 파일이 있긴 한데...
다른 곳에 이송 됐어요
One moment please, I'll check.
- 확실하오?
- 여기 그렇게 돼있어요
그럼 그때가 언제죠?
Were you working here last weekend?
1943년 12월이에요
No, day off.
- Did you do anything nice?
내가 봐도 될까요?
고맙소
My sister's wedding.
- 최근건가요?
- 오래됐어요
볼펜글씨예요
1943년엔 볼펜이 없었거든요
We did have a Mr. Liebling,
but he was transferred.
You sure?
- That's what it says.
- 볼펜 글씨요?
- 예
옛날 건데
볼펜이 있을지도 모르잖아요?
And when was that?
- Years ago, in December '43.
아뇨
여기에 파울러박사 서명이군요
May I take a look at this? Thanks.
아직 여기서 일하오?
Is this recent?
가끔요, 연로하시거든요
It's an old file.
- It's in ballpoint!
They weren't big on ballpoint in '43.
고맙소
Is that ballpoint?
Well, I'll be!
They didn't have ballpoints back then?
No.
This here
Dr. Fowler,
does he still work here?
- Just part-time, he's old.
Thank you.
산타 바이블
몰핀
잘 시간에 밤참하실거요?
누구요?
어떻게 들어왔지?
문틈으로
난 사립탐정이오
당신이 누구건 가택침입은
중죄에 속하오
경찰을 부르시지
누구건간에 아이스박스에
아편을 찾아낼 테니까
Time for your evening fix?
Who are you?
How did you get in here?
Through the mailslot.
I'm a private detective.
난 의사요. 난 주사할 의무가
주어진 사람이오
Breaking and entering is a crime,
whoever or whatever you are.
- Hey man, call the police!
의사양반
다른 사람들을 보라구요
내가 얘기하는 건 사용자가
누구냐하는거요
Which you won't do in case
they discover your opium den
in the icebox!
- 중독된 지 얼마나 됐소?
- 원하는 게 뭐요?
자니 리블링에 대해서요
오래된 환자들 이름을
다 기억할 수는 없소
I'm a doctor. I'm perfectly entitled
to keep pharmaceuticals at home.
이봐요, 날 바보취급말아요
Tell it to somebody else!
We're not talking about a Band-Aid
날 지방경찰관 취급하지 말고
똑바로 불란 말이오
or a tube of unguent. How long you
been hooked? - What do you want?
당신은 위층에서 솔트 씨와
일한 적이 있었소
Information about Johnny Liebling.
전쟁 때의 일을 기억할 수 없소
당신의 사건은...
I treated a patient
of that name many years ago.
회복할 수 없는 자라서...
알바니의 근처 병원에
이송한 환자요
I'm not fooling around.
여기 오기 전에 알바니에서
조사했지만 없었소
Either you give me some answers
or I'll call the police myself.
이송한건 거짓이오
그를 재빨리 돌려보냈소
최근 방문객이 있어서...
I've seen the works cooking upstairs,
and it ain't Mr. Salk's vaccine.
- 12년간 방문객은 없었소
- 유명한 자인데도?
He was an entertainer
during the war, a neuro case.
No chance of recovery, so I transferred
him to a V.A. hospital in Albany.
- 지금 어디 있지?
- 난 아직도 그를 모르오
이리와!
I hate to shake you up,
but I checked, and he's not there.
그가 환자로 있은 후의
일은 모르오
의사양반, 식은땀을 원하시나?
보라구
You faked the transfer.
Because he recently had a visitor,
the first in 1 2 years.
아이스박스 때문에 내가 좀
나가있기를 바라는군
Popular guy, eh?
방법은 오직 말하는 것뿐이야
Where is he now?
- I don't know . . . - Come here!
그렇다고 권총 자살할 텐가?
다시 묻겠다
그는 어디 있지?
I haven't seen him
since he was a patient here.
난 몰라
You're in a cold sweat! Look at you!
수년전 밤에 누군가 왔었소
You can't wait for me to leave
so you can raid the icebox.
차에 태워 어디론가 갔소
그 이후 다신 못 봤소
그가 차를 타?
그는 식물인간일 텐데?
The sooner you get out with it,
the sooner you can shoot up.
처음엔 코마상태였는데
곧 회복됐소
하지만 기억상실증에
걸리게 된거요
I'll ask you again: Where is he?
친구들
친구들이 누구지?
I don't know.
신사의 이름은 켈리요
에드워드 켈리
Some people came one night years ago.
He got in the car with them and left.
젊은 아가씨는 모르오
- 그녀는 차에 있었소
- 어디로 데려갔지?
He got into a car?
I thought this guy was a vegetable.
남쪽으로 갔소
남자 말로는 집으로 간다고 했소
At first he was in a coma
but he quickly recovered.
- 얼마나 받았지?
- 25,000 달러
But he still suffered from amnesia.
- 무슨 댓가지? / - 퓨리탄 일반병원에
환자로 남아있는 것처럼 꾸민 거요
The friends.
Who were the friends?
- His name was Kelley, Edward Kelley.
하지만 돌보지 않아
의심받을 텐데?
내가 왜?
매일 차트를 만들어 줬고...
The young lady I don't know.
She stayed in the car.
내가 하는 일에 누구도
질문하는 자가 없었어
Where did they take him? - Down South.
The man said: "We're taking him home."
자니 리블링이 어떻게 생겼지?
And what was the deal?
- $25,000.
모르오
전혀 어떤 모습인지 모르오
For what? - I was supposed to pretend
that he was still a patient in hospital.
그의 얼굴은 뭉개졌소
성형수술을 해야 했죠
머리끝까지 붕대로 감았소
Didn't the administration suspect?
- Why should they? I kept the charts
켈리가 올 때마다 만났소?
up to date. And no one asks questions
when the bills get paid.
기억하기에 너무 오래됐소
기억이 안나요
기억할 수가 없어...
그는...
심한 사투리를 썼는데...
남부 사투리...
Tell me about Johnny Liebling.
What did he look like?
- No idea. His face was damaged.
- 뭐?
- 솔직히 기억이 안나
좋아, 의사양반
이봐...
He had facial reconstruction.
He was in bandages the day he left.
좀 누어야겠어, 좋지?
나가서 치즈버거나 사와야겠어
몇 시간 쉬고 나면 기억이
날거야, 좋지?
What can you tell me about Kelley?
It's too long ago.
I only have a vague memory.
일어나
He was well dressed
and had a southern accent.
조심하라구
I truly don't remember.
- All right, Doc. Have a lie down.
그럼 낮잠 좀 주무시라구
여기에 누어서 말야
I'm going out to grab a cheeseburger.
조금 맘 편히 먹고 말야
Maybe a few hours cold turkey
will refresh your memory.
나갔다 와야겠어
내가 돌아오기 전에 아이스박스
안의 물건을 복용하겠지?
몇 시간 후에 돌아오면
원하는 대답 좀 하라구
Watch yourself!
We're going to take
a little nap, sit your ass down.
We're going to clear your mind.
I'm going out. When I get back,
I'll fix you some goodies
from the icebox, alright?
Tell me what I want to know
and you'll get rid of me forever.
자니
해리
돌아왔소, 의사양반
먹을 것도 사왔소
당신도 치즈버거를 좋아할 거야
I'm back, Doc!
I brought you a little something!
I didn't think
you'd want a cheeseburger . . .
- 안녕, 앨리
- 안녕, 해리
남자친구야?
- 그는 차도 있고 뭐든 있군?
- 그래요
- 안녕
- 또 만나
I will! Bye!
Hi, Ellie!
Is that your boyfriend?
He's got a car and everything?
See you later!
- 그를 만났소?
- 아뇨
- 왜죠?
- 힘들게 됐소
왜요?
그는 죽지 않았소
12년 전 자니는 걸어서
병원을 나갔소
멋진 양복에 붕대를 매서
얼굴도 모르고
두통까지
Did you see him?
- No.
켈리와 한 여자가 그를
데리고 간거요
Why not?
- It would've been difficult. - Why?
켈리가 누군지 아시오?
Why? Because he's not there.
켈리란 자가 파울러박사를
매수한 모양이오
Johnny Favorite
walked out of the clinic 1 2 years ago,
당신이 찾는 그자가
쓸모 있었나 보죠
in his best suit, with a new face
wrapped in bandages and a headache.
병원 치료로 회복됐소
He left with a guy called Kelley
and a girl.
Do you know this Kelley?
그러니까 우리의 자니가...
완전히 사라졌단 얘기군
It seems this Kelley paid off
some bent doctor called Fowler
그런 것 같소
to pinch hit for your guy.
He's covered up for him all these years.
민달팽이를 뭐라고
하는지 아시오?
아뇨, 뭐라고 하죠?
껍질 속에서만 산다고 하죠
Looks like our Johnny has
a perfect disappearing act.
- It seems so.
- 찾아내시오
- 아뇨, 찾을 수 없소
But you know what they say about slugs.
중요한 것 하나를
빼먹고 얘기했소
No, what do they say about slugs?
파울러 박사는...
They always leave slime in their tracks.
머리가 박살나
온통 아파트를 뒤덮었소, 알겠소?
- 파울러?
- 예, 파울러
- 당신이 죽였소?
- 아뇨, 죽이지 않았소
You'll find him.
- No, I won't find him.
경찰은 날 의심할거요
난 일당 125달러에 이번 일을
하고 있소, 그렇죠?
Because I left out one little detail.
이젠 살인 용의자가 됐소
그렇소, 그만 두겠소
This Dr. Fowler ended up dead
with his fucking brains blown out.
당신은 전문가죠, 엔젤씨?
만약 돈이 적다면 고려해 보겠소
Did you kill him?
- No!
사이퍼, 날 귀찮게 마시오
But the cops might think I did.
이번 일에 난 막다른 길에
서있는 셈이오
I took on a $1 25-a-day
missing persons job for you.
두 번째 길에서 일어나는 일을
관망하는 게 내 일이었소, 그렇죠?
바로 그런 일만 난 좋아하오
Now, I'm a murder suspect.
That's it! I'm out.
- 겁이 나오?
- 예, 겁나오
Such are the hazards of your profession.
If the fee bothers you, we'll adjust it.
내 변호사에게 즉시 당신에게
5,000달러를 지불하라고 하겠소
You bother me!
The closest I ever come to death
정히 싫다면 딴 사람을
물색해 보겠소
is watching a hearse go by
on 2nd Avenue. That's the way I like it.
- 5,000달러?
- 5,000이오
Are you afraid?
Yeah, I'm afraid.
자니란 자를
지독히 싫어하나 보군요
I'll instruct my lawyer immediately
to send you a check for $5,000.
셈이 흐린걸 싫어하죠
If you don't want the job,
I'll engage someone else.
어느 종교에서는...
계란을 영혼의 심벌이라 하죠
그걸 아시오?
5,000?
아뇨, 모르는데요
You want this Johnny pretty bad, eh?
I don't like messy accounts.
계란 드시겠소?
Some religions think the egg is the
symbol of the soul, did you know that?
아뇨, 됐습니다
병아리 생각이 나서요
No.
Would you like an egg?
No, thank you.
I got a thing about chickens.
거의 11시예요
늦었어요, 해리
미안
- 알아냈어?
- 그게 내가 할 일이죠
당신 비서가 될 것 같군요
타임지만큼 돈을 줄
능력이 없는걸...
반면에 이런 일이 자주
있는 것도 아니니까
자니, 도대체 어디있는거지?
It's after eleven, you're late.
- I'm sorry.
말했지만
자니 패이보릿은 가수예요
그리 유명한 것 같진 않아요
그는 스파이더 심프슨 오케스트라
밴드의 일원이었어요
You get it?
- If I lose my job,
죽지 않았어요
오직 스파이더만이 마을에 있어요
I'll come and be your secretary.
- 그는 어디 있지?
- 이미 마을을 다녀봤어요
I couldn't pay you what the "Times"
pays. Besides, they won't miss it.
테인케인 학교 도서관이
특별했죠
우리사장이 여러 해
스토리를 리서치 했죠
Hi, Johnny, where the fuck are you?
마지막을 알 수 없군
He really was a crooner, like you said.
I didn't realize he was so big.
스파이더는 양로원에 있어요
138번가에요
He was in a band called the Spider
Simpson Orchestra. They're all dead.
멋지군!
할렘에 가게 생겼으니까
자니와 기타 연주자인 투츠 스위트와
찍은 사진이 있어요
Only Spider is here in town.
- Where? - I wrote it all down.
몇 년간 누구도 그들을 본
사람이 없어요
The dyke in the archive is suspicious.
그는 마가렛 크루즈 마크라는
부잣집 딸과 약혼했었죠
My boss hasn't
researched the story in years.
루이지애나엔
그들의 것이 없어요
You can get the files.
뉴올리언스 고등학교에서
자니를 만났고...
Spider is in an old people's home
on 1 38th Street.
자니가 그녀를 차버리자 그녀는 고향에
돌아왔죠. 주문에 걸린 것처럼
Oh, I get to go to Harlem again.
There was a picture of Johnny
with Toots Sweet, a guitar player.
주문? 주문이 무슨 뜻이지?
No one's heard of him for years!
그러니까...난 잘 모르지만
야바위꾼 같은 거?
Johnny was engaged to a rich broad,
마치 속임수 같은 거죠
Margaret Krusemark.
Her dad owns half of Louisiana.
여러 가지를 조합해
점을 치는 거죠
Met him at a high school prom. Johnny
shit on her, and she went back to Daddy.
깊이 들어가진 못했지만
빠져들긴 해요
There's lots on their spells.
그래요. 그녀는 마녀 웰슬리를
알아요
Spells, what do you mean, spells?
마녀 웰슬리?
The eye of a newt,
- 잘 했죠?
- 그래. 잘했어
toe of a frog and that kind of shit?
- Seems she was a bit of a crackpot.
고객을 위해 종교적인 이름만
가지고 뭘해야한다지?
Casting spells
at society do's and stuff.
골든 타운이란 소스를 가지고
자니를 찾아야겠군
Didn't go down too well with
the lvy League stiffos.
우린 그가 어디있는지도 몰라
그 자신도 자신이 누군지 모를지 모르지
She was known as the Witch of Wellesly.
밴드리더가 있는 양로원과
할렘을 찾아가 보고
Did I do good?
기타 연주자
투츠 스위트를 만나봐야지
Great! So what've I got:
A religious loonie as a client.
- 내 생각엔...
- 흥분돼요?
I gotta find Johnny "Golden Tonsils"
and we don't know where he is.
괜찮아요?
And he probably doesn't know who he is.
I got a geriatric bandleader
in a home in Harlem.
I got a guitar player
called Toots Sweet.
What else have I got?
A hard-on?
Are you okay?
1955년 1월 3일
고객 루이스 사이퍼
변호사 와인셉 매킨토시
최소한 자니 패이보릿은 12년 전
사라 돗드에서 치료 후 사라졌다
에드워드 켈리와 한 여자의
소행으로 간주된다
January 3rd,
여자 신분은 알 수 없다
1 955. Client: Louis Cyphre.
Copy: Winesap & Mackintosh,
켈리는 파울러박사에게
25,000불을 줬다
패이보릿이 병원에 있는 것처럼
압력을 쓰기 위해서다
attorneys. As reported,
Johnny Favorite has not been
in the Sarah Dodd Clinic in
Poughkeepsie for the last 1 2 years.
의사는...
He was taken away by a man
called Edward Kelley and a girl.
이제 존재하지 않는다
자니의 사고로 그의 경력이
사라져 버리고...
The girl is unidentified.
Kelley paid a Dr. Fowler $25,000
to falsify reports
주변 사람들을 버리고 묻혀
사는 것 같다
stating
that Favorite was still in the hospital.
스파이더 심프슨은 자니의
밴드 리더다
스파이더는 지금 링컨 장로교의
양로원에 있다
The doctor is now deceased.
138번가에
자니에겐 친한 동료
투츠 스위트가 있다
Before Johnny's accident it seemed
like his career was going great,
투츠는 알주스로 돌아갔다
until he started to dump on everyone.
I tracked down Spider Simpson,
아프리카의 알주스가 아니고
뉴올리언스의 알주스다
마가렛도 돌아간 것 같다
어쩌면 자니도
Johnny's old bandleader. He resides
at the Lincoln Presbyterian Hospice
스파이더 말에 의하면 자니에겐
비밀의 사랑이 있다 한다
on 1 38th Street. Johnny also
had a good buddy, a guitar player
흑인여자 에벤지라인
프라우드풋이다
called Toots Sweet.
Toots went back to Algiers.
에벤지라인은...
That's Algiers in New Orleans.
할렘에서 약재상 종류의
가게를 차렸다 한다
마미 카터라고 불리는 가게다
I think maybe Margaret went back there,
and maybe Johnny, too.
Oh, yeah! According to Spider,
Johnny had a secret love.
이건 사이퍼에게
알릴 필요가 없다
A black lady
called Evangeline Proudfoot.
비밀의 사랑은
그녀의 비밀이다
Evangeline ran
some kind of spooky store in Harlem
오직 자니가
정기적으로 만난 사람은...
called "Mammy Carter's."
코니 섬에서 손금을 보는
마담 조라다
You don't
need to know that, Cyphre. I think
a secret love should stay secret.
The only person
who Johnny was seeing regularly
was a palm reader
in Coney lsland called Madame Zora.
당신이 이지요?
- 마지막 태양 같죠?
- 그래요
당신이 내게 도움이 될 거라고
해서 찾아왔죠
- 그래요?
- 예
난 마담 조라를 찾고 있소
물론 알죠. 전쟁 전에
아내의 친구였죠
- 그녀는 점쟁이죠?
- 예. 족집게라고 하더군요
Are you lzzy?
난 그런 마녀 따윈 아주 질색이오
Looks like the last bit of sun, eh?
아내를 이상하게 만들더라구요
아내는 침례교요
아, 여기...
The guy in the arcade over there
told me you might be able to help me.
코걸이 받아요
빨리 하나 받아요
I'm looking for Madame Zora. - I know
her, friend of the wife before the war.
도로에서 한 박스나 주운 거요
지금은 햇빛이 강하지 않아요
She was a fortune teller, right?
- And then some!
하지만 빗방울을 막아 줄거요
I hate those hocus-pocus bitches!
Her and the wife got along real well.
자니 패이보릿이란
이름 들어봤소?
- 가수?
- 예, 가수죠
Wife's a baptist. Oh, here!
마담 조라를 아직도 방문하나요?
듣긴 했지만 아는 게 전혀 없어요
아내가 알지 몰라요
Have a nose shield!
Go on, take one. I found a whole
boxful under the boardwalk.
라디오로 항상 그자의 노래를 듣죠
그자 노랜 다 알아요
- 물을 좋아하난 보죠?
- 아뇨, 싫어해요
There's not much sun right now.
Yeah, but it keeps the rain off too.
체중이 많이 나가니까
혈액 순환을 위한 거죠
Ever hear of a Johnny Favorite?
The singer?
- Yeah, he used to visit Madame Zora.
좋아요
감사합니다
Heard of him, but don't know nothing.
Ask the wife.
- 여름엔 여기서 뭘 하시죠?
- 쥐를 잡죠
She always sings stupid tunes
off the radio. She knows all that shit.
- 겨울엔요?
- 같아요
She likes the water, eh?
- She hates it.
She's getting on the heavy side.
She thinks it's good for varicose veins.
Alright, thanks.
What do you do here in the summer?
실례합니다!
Bite the heads off the rats.
당신 남편과 방금
얘길 나눴어요
And in the winter?
- The same.
마담 조라에 대해서요
전쟁 전에 그녀를 알았죠
마담 조라라고 했죠?
예, 집시인 점쟁이죠
그녀는 내 가게 건너편에서
부두교를 하고 있어요
그녀는 집시가 아녜요
그녀는 악마대왕이죠
Excuse me!
그녀는 큰 그릇에다
돈 훔치는 여자예요
I was just talking to your husband.
자니 패이보릿을
만나 본적이 있습니까?
I was inquiring about Madame Zora.
예, 잘 생겼죠
Yeah, I knew her before the war,
Madame Zora, you say?
항상 손님이 들끓었어요
그녀는 그에게 반했어요
Yeah, she was a gypsy fortune teller!
그를 골든 타운이라 불러요
그의 노랜 뭐든 알아요
Had the booth across the boardwalk from
me. She was a debutante not a gypsy,
마가렛 크루즈마크를 아십니까?
멍청한 소리 말아요, 친구
and she did
more than just read tea leaves.
마담 조라가
마가렛 크루즈마크요
Did you ever see her with a guy called
Johnny Favorite? - Yeah, he was cute.
어떻게 됐죠?
어느 날 짐을 싸서
고향으로 갔어요
She was stuck on him. He was called
"Golden Tonsils". I knew all his tunes.
물건을 챙겨서 말예요
자니 패이보릿을 만날
방법이 없을까요?
Have you ever
heard of a Margaret Krusemark?
없어요
어쩌면 무덤 속에 있겠죠
내 노래 들어보시겠소?
Don't be a gazoony, fellah!
Madame Zora was Margaret Krusemark.
당신을 위해 운다네
이제 당신 차례에요
당신이 울어요
Well what happened to her?
Packed up her stuff
and went back home, down south.
코마개 감사합니다
You have any idea
where I could find Johnny Favorite?
- 당장 떠나야겠어요
- 브룩클린으로?
- 아뇨, 루이지애나요
- 멋지군
No, maybe the cemetery.
Want to hear one of his tunes?
어디 가요?
Thanks for the nose shield.
I'm going to need it where I'm going.
In Brooklyn?
- Louisiana. - Nice.
Where'd he go?
래드 루스터
투츠와 그의 밴드
마담 크루즈마크
유색인종 좌석
- 오직-
FOR COLORED PATRONS ON LY
안녕
- 엔젤씨?
- 예
기다리게 해서 죄송해요
이른 시간이라서요
전화회선이 나빠서 4시인지
4시30분인지 몰라서요
정말 기막힌 장식이군요
예, 난 이곳이 행복해요
점을 쳐본 적이 없어서 그런데
오래 걸리나요?
Mr. Angel? Sorry to keep you waiting,
but you're a little early.
자세히 보려면 그래요
보통은 며칠이면 돼요
I had a bad line.
I didn't know if you said 4:00 or 4:30.
차?
This is a wild place you got here!
- Yes, I've been very happy here.
- 차 드실래요?
- 예. 고맙소
I've never had my fortune read before.
Does it take long?
I'll take the details now. It usually
takes a couple of days to do a chart.
가칠링, 자스민, 올롱?
- 올롱
- 올롱 좋아하는 사람도 있나요?
Tea?
Do you want some tea?
Yes, thank you.
- 피아노 치세요?
- 아뇨, 정확히는요
Darjeeling, jasmine or oolong?
노래는?
곡은 알아도 부르진 못해요
Not many people like oolong.
이 말라깽이는 누구죠?
- 제 아버지요
- 오, 실례했습니다
Do you play the piano?
No, not exactly.
걱정 마세요
역시 싫어해요
정말이지 옛날 해적영화에
나오는 해적 같아요
Sing?
I can carry a tune,
but no . . . not really.
- 이름이 뭐죠?
- 이든
이든
이든 크루즈마크
이든의 영화를
본적이 없는 것 같군요
Who is this mean looking guy?
My father.
I'm sorry!
Don't worry, he hates it too.
He looks like one of those guys
in an old pirate movie. What's his name?
불어 하세요?
Ethan.
- Ethan Krusemark . . .
- 난 브룩클린 출신이오
- 금연했으면 좋겠어요
Well, I tell you,
I never saw any of Ethan's movies.
어..그러죠
크림, 설탕?
아뇨, 그냥 먹죠
고마워요
출생일을 정확히
말해 주세요
물론
난 1918년 2월 14 생이오
Do you speak French?
I'm from Brooklyn.
I would prefer it if you didn't smoke.
- That's okay.
밸런타인데이죠
Cream or sugar?
Straight up is fine, thank you.
신기하군요
I need your exact date of birth.
내가 아는 사람과 똑같은
날이에요
정말요?
Sure!
I was born on February 14th . . .
많은 옛 군인들이 돌아왔거나
돌아오지 못한 군인이 있소
당신 친구와 같은 운명이라면
때론 구할 수도 있을 거요
. . . 1 91 8, on Valentine's day.
그렇지 않아요, 엔젤씨
사람들은 매우 달라요
당신도 같다고 생각지 않아요
How curious! I used to know a boy
who was born on that exact same day.
- 출생지는요?
- 뉴욕 브룩클린
Well, you know how it is,
all the soldiers home on leave and all.
- 그것도 당신친구와 같나요?
- 똑 같아요
Maybe we could pull your friend's chart
and save ourselves some time.
그럼 나도 그와 같을까요?
당신과 자니처럼 말이오
I don't think so. Every person
is very different. I don't think
you'd like his chart.
Place of birth?
당신과 자니 패이보릿처럼?
Brooklyn, New York.
Was your friend a jerk or something?
You could say that.
I guess you didn't get along.
- 당신 누구죠?
- 난 군대 옛 친구요
You and Johnny.
두 사람이 똑 같다고 하면...
군 전우를 찾아 보기위해서요
You and Johnny Favorite?
난 그저 그의 행적이 알고 싶어요
솔직히 난 밸런타인데이에
태어나지 않았소
난 자니의 미래에 흥미가
있어서요
Who are you?
- I was an old army buddy.
자니에겐 미래가 없어요
그는 죽었어요
I thought you two were kinda . . .
12년 전에 죽었어요
엔젤씨, 그만 나가 주세요
이봐요, 분명 숨기려는 모양인데
그에 대해 뭐든 알거예요
Look, I ain't no army buddy, I'm just
a guy who was paid to snoop around.
뭐든 다 알고 싶은 게 아니라...
To tell the truth,
I wasn't born on Valentine's day.
그는 죽었어요, 엔젤씨
It's Johnny's future I'm interested in.
아니라면 나와 있었을 거예요
어떻게요?
Johnny has no future, he's dead.
당신에게 큰 상처를 줬죠?
He died 1 2 years ago.
I'd like you to leave.
질문은 다 했어요, 엔젤씨
이봐요, 난 그자에 대해
많은걸 알고 싶은 게 아니에요
I know you're thinking who is this creep
poking his snitch in everything.
그가 당신을 놓치다니
어리석군요
사람들에겐 쉽게 적응되죠
안녕, 엔젤씨
I don't want to sound nosy, but . . .
- He's dead, Mr. Angel.
예쁘군요. 내 손금이 어떤지
보고 싶군요
And if he isn't, he is to me.
내 손을 잠시
당신에게 맡기고 싶어서요
He must've hurt you pretty bad!
We all have our scars.
보기보단 좋지 않군요
I don't know too much about the guy, but
he must've been stupid to let you go.
목걸이가 매우 예쁘군요
Lies and cruelty
come very easily to some people.
Pity, I really would've liked
to have gotten my palm read.
Then I could have held
your hand just a little longer.
I don't think you'd like what I see.
Very pretty necklace!
(마미 카터 약재상)
- 안녕
- 칸커글루 하이존 있나요?
- 파우더 아니면 통째로?
- 그런 건 잘 모르는데요
- 처음인가 보죠?
두 뿌리에 1불 20센트요
한 가지 질문이 있는데
내가 듣기론 당신은...
You got any High John
할렘 뒤에 퀸스상점은 없지만
거기에...
the Conquerer root?
- Powdered or hanging?
칸커글루 하이존
취급점이 있다던데요
I'm not really sure.
주인여자 에벤지라인이란
이름 들어봤나요?
Caught in the rain, eh?
주위엔 온통 에벤지라인이
주인이라고 불러요, 손님
시를 읊은 후죠. 시를 아세요?
Two roots, $1 .20.
예, 알아요
퀸스는 내가 듣기로는...
I have a question.
I had an acquaintance in Harlem
할렘에 상점은 '카터'라는 같은
이름을 쓰던데요
모두들 그 이름을 쓰는데...
who used to deal in the root.
여긴 '겁쟁이 존슨'이란
이름을 쓰게 되겠죠
Name was Evangeline. Heard of her?
그녀 이름은 프라우드풋이오
Practically everyone around here is
called Evangeline. After the poem.
- 에벤지라인 프라우드풋
- 예
Do you know it?
Yeah, I know it.
내가 알아요
그녀는 항상 이곳에 와요
뉴욕에 살면서도 말예요
This acquaintance had a store in Harlem
and it was the same name:
- 지금 어디 있는지 아시오?
- 병들어 죽었소
"Carter."
- Everybody uses the name, mister.
습지에서의 의식을 치른 후
겨우 아몬드 빌에 나타났죠
Like "Howard Johnson,"
but this is the real place.
그녀는 아는 누군가를 기다렸어요
Her name was Proudfoot.
- 시처럼 말이죠?
- 예, 시처럼
Evangeline Proudfoot?
1불 20센트요
I knew her. She used to come back all
the time when she lived in New York.
글쎄...누굴 기다렸죠?
말하지 않았어요
Do you know where she is now?
- She got sick and died.
She went back to the Holy Shelter
swamp and was buried in Armandville.
좋아요, 고맙소
She was waiting on some fellah.
- Just like in the poem? - Yep.
$1 .20.
- 일주일 묵을 거요?
- 예, 거의
Who was the guy?
- She never told.
Okay, thanks.
A week, you say?
- At the most.
왜 그래, 뭐야?
뭐야?
바보처럼 울긴
할머니 뵈러 가야해
저기 누가 있지?
할머니. 할머니
What is it?
Why are you crying?
We're going to Grandma. What's there?
가자
손 이리 내
Grandma.
Let's go.
Give me your hand.
비누
실례합니다
- 프라우드풋양?
- 예
미안해. 코니섬에서
어떤 자가 준거야
- 미안
- 울지 마
아가씨 어머니와
얘기 좀 했으면 하는데
예? 좀 늦으셨네요
어머니를 아세요?
I'm sorry!
I got these off a guy in Coney lsland.
아뇨, 만난 적은 없지만
어쩌면...
Some crazy guy.
내 질문에 답해 줄게
있을까 해서요
경찰이라도 되나요?
I'm sorry.
아뇨
난 해리 엔젤이오
Stop crying.
안녕하세요
난 사립탐정이오
I was hoping
I could talk with your mother.
- 그런데...
- 에피파니
- 에피파니?
- 예
You're a little late.
Did you know her?
어머니께서 예쁜 이름을
남기셨군, 에피파니
No, I never met her but I was hoping
she could answer some questions for me.
그 뿐이죠
Are you a cop?
솔직히 아주 솔직히 말해서...
No, my name is Harry Angel.
네 어머니 친구를 찾는데...
- 자니 패이보릿이라 부르지
- 예?
I'm a private detective.
엄마친구는 내가 다 알지만
패이보릿은 없어요
So what's . . .?
- Epiphany.
제길
Your mama left you
with a very beautiful name.
병아리는 질색이라서
And not much else.
Actually, I'm looking for
a friend of your mother's,
패이보릿은 아가씨 엄마
친구였어
전쟁 전에 뉴욕으로 돌아왔지
a guy called Johnny Favorite.
그런 얘기한적 없어요
I met all her friends
but never anyone called Favorite.
엄만 남자가 많아요
남자를 좋아했거든요
투츠 스위트는 아니?
Shit!
그는 패이보릿의 친구인데
만나 본 적 있니?
I got a thing about chickens.
유명한 기타 연주자인가 본데
오늘밤 구경 가려고 해
This Favorite was friends with your
mother in New York city before the war.
난 이곳에 묵을 건데
마을 호텔이야
Well, she never told me.
Mama had a lot of guys. She liked men.
혹시 뭐라도
기억나는 게 있으면
내게 도움이 될거야
How about a guy called Toots Sweet?
그러니 전화해줘
He was a friend of Favorite. Know him?
- No. - He was a good guitar player.
I was going to catch his act tonight.
아주 예쁘구나, 에피파니...
이름과 옷이 어울려
I'm going to be
staying in town, in a hotel.
If you remember anything
that might help me,
give me a call.
병아리들!
이봐요!
자니 패이보릿은 왜 찾죠?
꼭 찾아야해
그를 찾아야 할 거래가 있어
You're a very pretty girl, Epiphany,
your name suits you.
아마 땅속에 있을 거예요
그럼, 삽을 사야겠군
These crazy chickens!
What are you after him for,
Johnny Favorite?
I'm not after him. I'm just being paid
to find out where he is.
그녀는 당신을 소유하네
He could be 6 feet under.
- Then I'll have to buy a shovel.
고통이라 불리는 잔을
난 가지고 있다네
몇 곡의 노래를
당신이 모두 가져도
난 상관안해
더 이상 떠날 것도 없어
나와의 블루스를
그건 자신이야
그 모든 건 자신이야
비오는 날에
투츠에게 점수를
그건 자신이야
농담할 시간이죠?
How are you, sugar?
무대에서 정말 멋진 노래를
부르더군요, 스위트씨
- 투츠라 부르시오. 고맙소
- 한잔 사도 될까요?
아뇨, 내 집에서만 들죠
두 자매 칵테일만을
저녁거리도 걱정이오
이 직업을 차버리던지 해야지
듣기론 뉴욕에서도
몇 년간 연주 했다죠?
전쟁 전에요
딕키 월즈 바아를 운영했잖아요
Some beautiful tune
당신은 자니 패이보릿과 함께
꽤 유명했다죠?
you were singing there, Mr. Sweet.
- Toots, son! Thanks. - Buy you a drink?
Mine's on the house. Special cocktail.
Whatever's in it gives a big kick.
그렇소, 예전에 그자와
날렸던 게 기억나오
그자와는 동료였죠?
아니, 내 노래를 녹음한 적은 있지만
친구로서 판매한 적은 없어
You know, I heard you play
years ago in New York.
당신 책 작가로군
Before the war
at the old Dickie Wells Bar.
필요해서죠
난 대중작가예요
아시다시피 제가 하는 일은...
제가 하는 취재는 자그마한...
You were having it up pretty good
with a guy called Johnny Favorite.
자니와 스파이더 심프슨
오케스트라예요
난 드럼판 치는 듯 한 소란스런
동료는 기억나지 않소
Yeah, I vaguely remember.
- You and he were buddies, weren't you?
가보시게, 젊은이. 시간이 별로 없어
소변보고 또 일해야 하니까
No, he recorded one of my songs.
Say, are you a dick or a book writer?
또 보세. 난 두 자매 칵테일을 들테니
자넨 내키는 대로 글을 써버리라구
Neither. I'm a journalist
and I'm doing this piece
신문사 사람들은
보통 그러지 않나?
about Johnny
and the Spider Simpson Orchestra.
Spider played them drums
like two jackrabbits fucking!
Haven't got much time. Got to piss,
spit and get back to work.
Try one of those cocktails. Then you can
make the whole thing up as you like.
That's what you usually do, anyway.
- 여보게, 소변 좀 보자구
- 이봐요
난 당신을 알아요. 자니 패이보릿과
에벤지라인 얘길 하자는 게 아니라...
어렵게 얘기할 필요 없어
난 아는 게 없어
요즘엔 오직 두 자매 칵테일만
있으면 된다구. 이봐
I can't even take a piss!
I just wanted to talk about Johnny
Favorite and Evangeline Proudfoot.
I'm too big to go hiding under beds.
I don't know nothing.
- 이건 뭐죠, 투츠?
- 신경 쓸 거 없어. 난 소변을...
I'm only interested in cocktails. Fuck!
여기서 당장 나가지 않으면
다신 걸어 다닐 수 없다
결코 후손이란 없어
제발, 병아리 생각하느라고 그랬어
티파니를 들이지 말고
문밖을 나서지 말아요
What's going on? - Nothing! Mind your
own business. I want to piss!
할 얘기가 있어!
Get outta here,
or you'll wish your little white ass
was never born.
Please! I've got a thing about chickens.
이봐...
거짓말 시간은 끝났어, 알아?
너와 에피파니가 한걸 잘 봤어
너와 많은 병아리들도 말야
잘 들어
브룩클린에서 부터의
모든 거짓은 충분해
이곳 밥스 타운을 알잖아
프라우드풋 여자는
어떻게 된거지?
그 앤 맘보야. 13살 때부터
엄마 뒤를 따른 교주야
End of bullshit time!
당신이 자니 패이보릿을 봤을 땐
병아리 따윈 없었지?
I've had a
good look at you and young Epiphany
doing your hot shoe number
with the chicken.
아직도 그가 맘보 따위를 원하나?
난 오직 전쟁 전에만 그를
봤다고 했잖아
Listen!
I ain't up on this voodoo shit.
I'm from Brooklyn.
- 그럼 존에게 닭고기 요리란 게 뭐지?
- 그건 내 입이 크다는 뜻이야
We ain't all Baptists here.
- What's with this Proudfoot girl?
그 걸로는 안 되겠어, 투츠
네 입에 뭘 해야 하는지 알아?
말해 주지
She's a mambo priestess, like her mom.
Has been since she was 1 3.
When was the last time you saw
Johnny Favorite at a chicken dance?
내 호텔 번호를 알려줄테니
내게 전화해
어떤 정보든 간에
He used to run around with Ma mambo.
- I ain't seen him since before the war.
다음부턴 결코 닭 요리가...
And the chicken foot in the john?
- It means I got a big mouth.
특별 배달되진 않을 거야
돕지 않으면 말야
It's not big enough.
What's this fucking star
내가 걱정 되는걸 말해 주지
아무 닭이나
내겐 좋은 닭은 아냐
in your mouth? I'll tell you what.
I'll give you my hotel number.
Gimme a call if you hear anything.
You never know.
Next time you get a delivery of a
chicken foot, you might need help.
As far as I'm concerned,
any dead chicken is a good chicken.
경찰이란
좋은 소식이란 없지, 그렇죠?
탐정은 잠꾸러기로군
천국의 꿈이나 꾸고 말야
그건 너무 거리가 멀군
제길, 너무 많이 새는 모양이군
이거. 자네 이름이지?
Only cops and bad news don't knock.
Only private dicks sleep late.
Quite a dream you were having!
- I was on my way to Mandalay.
당신 호텔이고?
Shit! There's some leak up there!
- 거길 갔었군, 그렇지?
- 그래. 손으로 쓴거야
Here! ls this your name?
그밖엔?
그날 밤 우리가 발견한
기타 연주자에 대해...
말 좀 해줘야겠어
- 투츠 스위트가 죽었소?
- 그래, 투츠 스위트
That your hotel?
You're standing in it, ain't you?
- Your handwriting?
이번엔 무척 빠르게
진행됐어
어떻게 죽었죠?
I think so.
솜씨 좋게
자신의 성기를 절단 냈어
Then perhaps you can tell us
why we found it in the hand
of a dead guitar player.
별로 솜씨 없군
누군가 성기를 잘라
입속에 넣어 질식 시켰어
그의 아파트는 온통
그의 피로 장식을 했지
Toots Sweet is dead?
언제 그를 만났지, 엔젤?
This one wasn't so quick,
this one took time.
어제 한시쯤 그와 인터뷰를 했소
How did he die?
- 무슨 이유로 접선했지?
- 실종자 문제로
Technically?
Asphyxiation by his own genitalia.
누구지?
And not so technically?
12년 전에 투츠와 찍은
사진의 주인공이지
They cut his dick off
and choked him with it.
그를 찾는 자가 누구지?
Then redecorated his apartment
with his blood.
뉴욕 변호사의 프라이버시를
위해 말해 드릴 수 없지
When did you see him? - I interviewed
him around 1 :00. - About what?
이름은?
이보라구요
와인셉이오
그의 전화번호와
주소까지 알고 싶다면
A missing person.
저 친구 책속에 있을 테니
시험해 보라구
Who?
선데이 'W'야, 천재양반
A guy who took a walk 1 2 years ago.
당신 야구선수 테드 윌리엄스 알지?
There was a photo of him and Toots.
- Who is the party you're looking for?
I can't say.
I'm working for a New York lawyer.
허먼 와인셉이군요
Name?
- Come on, man!
좋아, 그자들이...
Winesap!
You want his number, his address?
그거야
Ask Tess Truehart over there,
it's in the book.
자네와 그 프라이버시랑
점심이나 나누게
Under "W," genius! - Do you know
Ted Williams, the baseball player?
멀리 나다니진 말게
곧 그 변호사와 대면해야 하니까
Alright, is that it, guys?
미키 마우스 클럽을 보면
어떤 줄 아나?
That's it.
오늘이 무슨 날인지 아나?
You can go eat lunch,
but don't stroll too far.
오늘은 수요일이야
아무 일도 일어나지 않는 날이지
Not until we talk to this lawyer.
Ever watch the "Mickey Mouse Club?"
Do you know what today is?
Today is Wednesday.
It's "anything can happen" day.
이봐요, 노래를 원하시오?
예, 당신을 위해 부르죠
Hey man, do you want a tune?
Yeah, I got a tune for you.
이봐요, 여러분
당신에게 한 말이오
제길. 좀 서둘러요
나머지를 팔겠소?
- 10센트요, 손님
- 물론. 잠깐만요
Hiya, boys!
Same to you.
I'm getting kinda hungry.
제길, 빌어먹을
Do you want to sell some of those?
1 0 cents a sack.
- Sure, give me a sack.
잘 들어. 마가렛 크루즈마크란 노인이
처음부터 널 길들이진 않을 거야
이것 좀 치우란 말야
아니면 개가 네 얼굴을
물어뜯어 버릴 거다
빌어먹을
Listen good! Margaret Krusemark's old
man wants you on the first train home.
Take that fucking thing away from me!
Don't, or the dog will bite
your fucking face clean off.
무슨 일이죠?
개가 물었어
원하는 게 뭐죠?
당장은 세탁 좀 해야겠어
- 저 에피트파니...
- 에피파니
에피파니. 뭘 좀 물어볼게 있어
그날 밤 너와 투츠 스위트가
있는 걸 봤는데...
What happened to you?
숲속에서 그 의식을 봤어
A dog bit me.
마치 무슨 파티를
하는 것 같았어
So, what do you want?
자유국가에서 그게 무슨 문제죠?
Right now, I need a laundry.
병아리도 있었어, 그렇지?
그래요. 난 병아리에 대한
노래를 부른 게 기억나요
Listen, Epiphiny . . .
- Epiphany.
들어봐, 에피파니
투츠가...투츠가 죽었어
There's something I want to ask you.
나도 들어서 알아요
The other night I saw you and Toots
boogying with the cock-a-doodle.
- 슬프겠군
- 아뇨, 그렇지 않아요
투츠를 본 걸 아는 사람은
오직 나뿐이야
Looked like you were having some party.
What's your problem?
It's a free country.
투츠에게 닭을 포장해서
보내긴 싫었지?
그래요, 투츠는 입이 커요
Not for chickens.
- Oh yeah, your thing about chickens.
조만간 경찰이 조사에 나설 거야
Listen, Toots is . . .
그는 네 종교에
무척 열성이던데
Toots is dead.
- I know, I heard.
그는 결코 어림도 없어요
당신도요
You set him up.
- No, I didn't.
네가 닭을 죽여
국을 끓인다는 건 알고 있어
You were the only one
that knew I was seeing Toots.
살인사건을 맡은 게 아닐 텐데요, 엔젤씨?
자니 패이보릿은 어떻게 됐죠?
You sent the
gift-wrapped chicken foot, didn't you?
- 겨우 이제야 그를 기억했나보군?
- 예, 그는 내 아버지예요
Toots had a big mouth.
I guess he did,
judging by what the cops found in it.
Quite a cute religion! - Nailing a man
to a cross ain't so cute either!
민스?
- 나중에 아기를 데려가도 되죠?
- 괜찮아
You've got to kill the chicken
to make the soup, eh?
We don't go around murdering people.
What about your Johnny Favorite?
이봐, 억누르고 있던 걸
이제 뭐든지 털어놔봐
할 말 없어요
Now you remember him after all.
- Yes, he was my father.
자니는 전쟁에서 돌아왔어요
엄마는 기다리다 죽었어요
간단한 얘기죠
에피파니, 너무 많은 사람들이
주변에서 죽어가고 있어
I'll pick the baby up later, okay?
- He'll be all right.
그는 전에 루이지애나에 있었어
Anything you're holding out,
now is a good time to tell.
노인이 도울 수 있어
- 남편은 있니?
- 아뇨, 남편은 없어요
Nothing to tell.
Johnny never came back from the war.
저런, 너무 예쁜 눈을
가지고 있어, 에피파니
Mama waited and Mama died.
Sad and simple.
정말이야
너무 아름다워
눈은 속마음을
자세히 말해주고 있어
There's too many dead bodies
floating around, even for Louisiana.
- 무서워하는걸 알아
- 견딜 수 있어요
I'd tell your old man
to look out for you.
You do have a husband?
- No.
- 이봐, 들어봐...
- 무슨 소식이 있으면 전화할게요
No?
Jesus, you've got beautiful eyes!
이봐
없어도 전화 해
Really.
The kind of eyes
that tell what's going on inside.
알았지?
Right now, you're scared.
- I'll manage.
Listen . . .
- Yes, I'll call you if I hear anything.
Call me if you don't.
Alright?
소식이 있어요
- 고맙소
- 천만에
I have a message for you.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
와줘서 고맙네
마을까지 올 줄은 몰랐소
난 바톤 보그와 관련된 걸 얘기했소
그래서 마을에 왔고...
또한 당신 진행상황을
알고 싶어서요
아직요
진행은 잘 되어가요
만약에 차라리 뒤엎는다면
그건 자니 패이보릿은 없다는 거요
I'm so glad you could come.
- I didn't know you were in town.
불행이군요
알아요. 내가 연관된 자들을 꼽던...
3단계는...
I'm speaking in Baton Rouge and thought
I'd catch up on your progress.
- 단계?
- 예
송장이 됐소, 사이퍼 씨
살해됐죠
I'll tell you,
the progress ain't too good.
살해?
I've found out a lot of stuff,
but so far . . . no Johnny Favorite.
난 자니를 치료해준
파울러 박사를 만났죠
How unfortunate! - All I've got is a
belly full of hocus-pocus and . . .
부두교인 투츠 스위트를 만났구요
그는 오줌 누는 몸의 일부분으로
목이 막혀 질식해 죽었소
3 stiffs.
Dead bodies, Mr. Cyphre.
여긴 교회요, 엔젤씨
Murders.
한 말씀드리죠
여긴 교회이지만...
주변엔 해괴한 많은 종교
집단들이 있어요
I got Fowler, Johnny's doctor,
bumped himself off.
이해 못하겠어요
너무 추해요
This old voodoo guy Toots Sweet.
사람들은 이 세상에 너무 충분한
종교집단이 있어서...
인간을 행복하게 만들기 보다는
서로 증오하게 한다고들 하지
He got choked to death with a part of
the body meant for pissing with . . .
내가 그런 말을 했소?
말씀드리죠, 사이퍼 씨
This is a church!
자니 패이보릿 주변엔 사랑하는
사람들이 많지 않았어요
The whole thing has to do with
religion. It's very weird.
난 매우 나쁜 운명이에요
그건 날 장난감으로 끝낼 거예요
난 이미 두사건의 살인
용의자로 돼 있어요
I don't understand it. It's ugly.
경찰은 투츠 스위트의 손에서
내 이름과 주소를 알아냈어요
They say there's enough religion to
make men hate each other but not love.
알아요
와인셉이 말해줬소
Do they say that?
조심해야겠소, 엔젤씨
I'll tell you something. There wasn't
much love around for Johnny Favorite.
그럼 세 번째는?
세 명이 살해됐다고 했소
자니의 사회적인 친구
마가렛 크루즈마크를 조사했었죠
He was bad luck!
It's starting to rub off on me. I'm a
murder suspect already in two cases.
- 그 여자 아시오?
- 어렴풋이
The police found my name
and my address in Toots Sweets' hand.
어렴풋이?
모두들 어렴풋이라 하는 소리에
이젠 진력이 났소
I know, Winesap told me.
You must be careful, Mr. Angel.
어렴풋이란 소린 이젠 내 목을 조르고
질식시키려 든단 말이오
그럼, 사이퍼 씨
그녀를 압니까, 모릅니까?
And the third murder?
I checked out Johnny's old society
girlfriend, Margaret Krusemark.
그녀를 알지만
자세히는 모르오
말씀드리죠
그녀는 나의 속임수를 시작했소
Do you know her?
- Vaguely.
난 내가 자니의 생일인
2월 14일생이라 했죠
Vaguely? I'm a little fed up
with fucking vaguely.
누군가 자신의
밸런타인 카드를 잘라서
"Vaguely" is putting a noose
around my neck and I'm choking, so . . .
그것으로 그는
그녀의 심장을 잘라냈소
Did you know her or not?
I knew about her,
but I never actually knew her.
그녀는 자신의 미래는
점칠 수 없었던 것 같소
Tell you what, she was doing my chart.
미래는 평상시와 같지 않소
엔젤씨
I gave her Johnny's birthday,
February 14th.
- 엔젤 종말은?
- 아무것도 가진 게 없소
자니를 아는 모든 사람들이
피해를 당한 것 이외에는
Except someone got to her and
took out their own Valentine's card.
또한 내가 나설수록
더욱 피해가 간다는 것을
They slit her open
and cut out her heart.
여기 앉아 있는 순간까지 두려워요
알겠소?
I guess she couldn't
predict the future for herself.
그럼 지옥이 왜 날
원하는 지 말해주겠소?
도대체 어떻게 돼가는거요?
The future isn't what it used to be.
다만 자니 패이브릿이 죽으면
그게 내겐 다요
And your conclusions?
- I haven't any.
엔젤씨
All I know is that Johnny is running
around bumping off everyone he knew.
난 구식이지만 분명한 게 있소
눈에는 눈이란 걸 알거요
그건 거요
And more and more,
it's me who's on the line for it.
I'm being set up
and it's scaring the shit out of me.
- 빌어먹을 당신은 누구요, 사이퍼?
- 말 조심해요
So why don't you just level with me
and tell me what the fuck is going on?
난 이따위 교회는
상관없소, 알겠소?
Just Johnny Favorite
and the debt that's owed to me.
교회는 날 압박할 뿐
난 교회를 좋아하지 않소
- 당신 생각이오?
- 예, 그래요
I have old-fashioned ideas,
about honour.
난 브룩클린 출신이오
An eye for an eye, things like that.
난 마을에 머무를 거요
만약 돈이라도 필요하면...
Who the fuck are you?
아뇨, 돈은 됐어요
Watch your language!
만약 내가 잘 못되면
내게 줄 5,000불을...
I don't give a fuck,
if this is a church.
그저 죽을 전기의자나
하나 사주시오
I don't like churches.
- Are you an atheist?
Yes, I'm from Brooklyn.
I'll be in town for a day or two,
let me know what else you find,
and if you need more money . . .
- No!
But if I'm not careful,
that 5,000 bucks you gave me could
buy me a seat on the electric chair.
안녕
두려움의 눈엔 거짓이 없지
일어나. 들어 가자구
- 아기는 어디 있지?
- 민시네요. 이젠 대리모가 됐어요
아이가 열넷이나 돼요
그러니 문제없어요
Frightened eyes never lie.
이봐, 에피파니
매우 시골티가 나는데 여기 아니면...
Come on! Come inside!
각 방으로?
난 괜찮아요
난 한잔해야겠어
한잔 하겠어?
아무튼 한잔할테지
Where's your child?
- He's at Mincie's. She'll bring him.
She's got 14 of her own,
so he'll be okay there.
이건 개인적인 얘기야, 에피파니
You're welcome to stay here,
or I can get you a room.
도대체 왜 네 엄마는 자니 패이보릿 같은
남자를 만났는지 말야
No, it's okay.
난 전혀 알지 못해요
전혀 말을 안 해줬거든요
I'm going to have a drink. Want one?
솔직히 얘기해봐
그자는 망나니야
Well, have one anyway.
엄마는 그를 그리워했어요
말해주지...
많은 남자들이 있었는데
방문을 자주했어, 알지?
I've been thinking . . .
What the hell did your mother see in
a guy like Johnny Favorite?
말 못 할게 뭐있어요?
그 자식 얘기만 하면
엄만 아파했어요
I don't know. Whatever he had,
it sure stole her heart away.
전혀 그자 얘길 안하셨나?
To tell you the truth,
the guy was a creep.
- 자니?
- 그래
She sure missed him.
- 두 가지가 있어요
- 뭔데?
What does a lady see in a guy
who runs around chopping up pigeons?
엄마가 하고 싶어 하는 말은...
자니 패이보릿은 악마와 가깝댔어요
그래서 모두들 모여든 거래요
They say it's always the bad-asses
who make a girl's heart beat faster.
- 또 다른 말은?
- 굉장한 정력가래요
Did she ever say anything about him?
- 몇 살이지, 에피파니?
- 17
Just two things.
- What?
That Johnny Favorite was as close to
true evil as she ever wanted to come.
아이를 갖기엔 너무 어리잖아?
충분해요
What else?
- 아기 아버진?
- 누군지 몰라요
That he was a terrific lover.
미안
솔직히 말해 왜 이런 집을
얻었는지 모르겠어
How old are you?
1 7.
Kind of young to have a kid, isn't it?
대나무 오두막이예요
Old enough.
몰락한 귀족이라고 하면
딱 어울리죠
그래
난 몰락한 귀족이야
Where did the father go?
- I never knew him.
I'm sorry.
- 정말 몰락한 귀족이에요
- 바로 그 말이야. 딱 맞았어
I don't know why I took this room.
- 거기엔 신이 있어요
- 그럼 신의 아기를 임신했던 거군
I can't believe this!
알만하군. 미안
It was a Bambouche. When spirits
possess you, it's called "chevalier."
난 전혀 성경험이 없어요
I know that: Chevrolet.
Chevalier. - That's what I said:
Chevrolet. - Mounted by the gods.
So the gods got you pregnant?
I understand now. I'm sorry.
I'm not.
It was the best fuck I ever had.
추실래요?
여기서?
예, 여기서
개한테 물려서
움직이기 어려울 텐데
글쎄요
기분은 같아요
Want to dance?
함께 추실까요?
- 약속할게 있어
- 뭘요?
Here?
Yes, here.
닭은 안 돼
- 좋아요
- 일어나
I got bit by a dog this morning,
I can't move around.
You won't feel a thing.
Alright, I'll dance with you.
But you've got to promise.
- What's that? - No chickens!
알았어요, 나가요
당신 노크인줄 알았소
최소한 이 시각까지
늦잠을 잔 이유가 있겠군
자니 엔젤
우린 흑인촌을 놓치지 않았지
유색인종은
자기들끼리 유지하니까
이봐요
여긴 어떻게 왔소?
- 다친 거요?
- 개가 물었소
마가렛 크루즈마크가
당신이 찾던 실종자요?
Alright, I'm coming!
I should've recognised the knock.
- 아뇨, 왜죠?
- 그녀가 죽었소
At least you got a reason
for sleeping late.
흑인 기타 주자는
말할 나위도 없어
Down here we don't mess with jigaboos.
The colored folks keep to themselves.
그는 2주일간 부두교 86에
서로 간에 있었어
크루즈마크 말야
I'm not from down here.
- You cut yourself?
그녀는 루이지애나에 돈 많은 가족이 있어
무슨 돈이지?
Dog bit me.
두 사람을 같은 주에 수사하는데
무슨 연관이지?
Somebody called Margaret Krusemark
figure in your missing persons case?
단순한 상황이지
어떻게?
그녀도 성기를 잘라냈나?
No, why? - She's dead.
That nigger guitar player of yours,
아냐, 누군가 심장을 도려냈어
마치 도살한 것처럼 말야
he didn't matter a shit. He was into
voodoo, they 86 each other every week.
이봐, 난 실종자 수색중이오
살인범이 아니라구, 알겠소?
But this Krusemark dame, she comes
from a Louisiana money family.
당신을 고용한 자가 누군지
알아야겠어
뉴욕에 있는 변호사라고
이미 말해줬잖소
Two people bumped off in a week,
what's the connection?
만나봤지만 당신처럼
울타리 입을 가진 자더군
Similar circumstances!
고객까지 물어보려고?
집어치우고 저리 꺼져버리시지 그래?
Did she have her dick cut off too?
- No!
Some fucker cut her heart out,
neat as a butcher.
그자식이 여기서 통할 것 같아?
루이지애나 법을 따라야 해
Look, mine's
a missing persons, it's not a murder.
대도시 행세를 하려면
너희 뉴욕으로 꺼져버려
I want the name of the party you're
looking for. - Talk to the lawyer.
이건 크루즈마크의 피야
I did. A fancy mouthpiece, gave me the
same big city shit as you.
그녀는 점술과 마술 같은 걸로
점을 치지
그 사람은 전혀 무참하게
살해당할 만한 이유가 없어
What should I say? Why don't you and
Effie Klinker just fuck off
만약 내가 더럽혔다면
저안에 검둥이보고 치우라고 해
and leave me alone?
- You ass-wipe!
You play jump rope with Louisiana law
and I'm going to stick
your big city smarts
right up your New York ass.
This Krusemark was into black magic
and all that shit.
내 사랑의 꿈 그 꿈 위로
Nothing is worse for a cop than people
who get killed for nutso reasons.
오, 난 필요해
난 할거야
Sorry about the mess.
Maybe your nigger can clean it up.
당신은 너무
아름다워
만일 내가 꼭
당신의 시간을 잡는다면
다시금 나의 것이네
마치...
네가 만든 노래니?
자니 패이보릿 노래이고
엄마가 가끔 내게 불러준 노래예요
- 괜찮아요?
- 그래
너는 검고 꼭
너의 시간을 잡으리
What are you singing?
It's by Johnny Favorite.
My mother used to sing it all the time.
지난 끈은 용서됐으니
인생은 자유가 되리라
You okay?
Shit!
원하는 게 뭐요, 엔젤씨?
- 다 아는 줄 알았는데요
- 내가 왜죠?
부두교를 추적하다보니
오늘 이곳까지 오게 된거요
자니 패이보릿을 찾고 있소
내가 아는 건 댄스 밴드에서
돌아온 후 죽은 것뿐이오
좋아요. 댄스밴드는 당신 딸까지
살해할 필요가 없었을 거요
누가 보내 왔죠?
What do you want, Mr. Angel?
말 할 수 없소
I thought you knew.
- Why should l?
돈을 드리죠
그들도 줬소
Two of your morons with a matching
poodle have been chasing me for days.
12년 전 당신은 당신 딸과 폽킵시에서
패이보릿을 닫힌 뚜껑을 열고
끄집어내었소
I'm looking for Johnny Favorite.
못된 의사를 25,000불에 매수하여
자니를 실종케 했소
As far as I know,
that dance band scumbag is dead.
지난주 까지는
아주 잘 됐겠죠
That dance band scumbag
probably killed your daughter.
당신은 에드워드 켈리란
이름을 썼소
Who is employing you?
- I can't say.
엔젤, 개인적인 얘기는 안에서
감보를 먹으며 얘기합시다
I'll pay.
- So do they.
1 2 years ago, you and your daughter
snatched Favorite from the nut hatch.
그렇군요
속이 쓰린걸 보니
미안하오
조류요리는 질색이라서요
You gave a junkie doctor 25 grand to
pretend Johnny was still there.
내가 즐기는 감보가
당신 속을 약간 쓰리게 하나 보군요
You did a good job until a week ago.
You used the name Edward Kelley.
Let's go over here. It's a little
private and you can sample our Gumbo.
I've got an acid stomach.
Cajun cooking kills me.
내가 에드워드 켈리였소
파우어에게 25,000불을 줬구
Pity about your stomach!
You'd have enjoyed our Gumbo.
- 패이보릿이 당신을 압니까?
- 아뇨
몽유병자처럼 걸었죠
우린 창밖에서 상황을 지켜봤구요
어디서 그를 데려갔소?
1943년 새해 타임 스퀘어요
군중들 틈에서 사라져 버린 거요
그는 영원히 살기위해 걸었죠
그가 사라지는 걸 봤소
군중들 틈에 사라지라고
25,000불을 지불했단 말이오?
I was Edward Kelley.
It was me who paid Fowler the 25 grand.
내 딸을 위한 거요
Did Favorite know you?
- No.
내 딸의 능력을 위해선
자니가 꼭 필요했기 때문이오
He acted like a sleep walker. He looked
out of the window at the lights.
그녀 방에서 손을 보고
나도 짐작했소
영광의 손이오
Where were you taking him?
- Times Square. New Years Eve, '43.
사람들에게 행운을 주지
그 손은 사형당한 사형수의
오른 손을 자른 거요
We dropped him off in the crowd,
and he disappeared forever.
그건 마가렛의 피지
Or so we thought.
- 마술처럼?
- 어쩌면. 왜?
You're telling me you paid 25 grand
for a guy and lost him in a crowd?
- 마가렛을 공주로 만들...
- 악마지
I did it for my daughter.
악마는 지옥에나 있소, 엔젤씨
Some sort of hocus-pocus she and Johnny
were fooling with. She was obsessed.
누구나 그녀의 말
한 마디 한마디를 받아들였어
마가렛은 악마가 아냐
I know,
I found a mummified hand in her room.
그 앤 어릴 때부터
이상한 아이였지만...
The hand of glory.
It's supposed to open any lock.
그 앤 시작하기 전에
타로 카드부터 시작했어
시작하는 게 좋아
It was the right hand of a murderer, cut
off while his neck was in the noose.
가정교사 하인이 알아
가정교사, 하인?
뭐든 거짓말만 내뱉는군
That's what Margaret believed.
Black magic! - Black, white, what's the
difference? Margaret was always . . .
어떻게 시작하는지 알고 싶나?
악마가 아니면 양이란 거야
Evil.
- Evil as a dunghill.
어둠의 왕자는 힘으로 보호해
- 그런 거짓말을 하다니
- 날 믿지 않아도 난 어쩔 수 없어
Everyone speaks about someone else.
Margaret wasn't evil.
똑바로 불지 않으면
사형시켜 버린다는 말밖엔 할 수 없어
She was a strange kid! She was into
Tarot cards before she could read.
자니 패이보릿은 내 딸에게
엄청남 힘을 줬어
Who got her started?
- Some maid, or governess, who knows.
언젠가 내 방에서
그가 연기처럼 나타나는걸 봤어
그는 날 깊숙이 바라다 봤어
Everything you tell me
is a crock of shit!
그는 안전한 존재가 됐어
그는 그의 영혼을 팔았어
You got her started!
- 그따위 말을 믿어 달란 거야?
- 내 말을 다르지 않으면 말할 수 없어
You're a devil worshipper! - The Prince
of Darkness protects the powerful.
그따위 거짓말은 치우란 말야
빌어먹을 녀석아!
Shit!
- I can't help if you don't believe it.
- 그는 침묵을 위한 영혼이라 했어
- 침묵이라고? 똑 바로 말해!
Come straight with me, you slime-bag,
or I'll save the state an execution!
- 빌어먹을. 그냥...
- 모두가 죽음이 닥친다고 했어
I introduced
Johnny Favorite to my daughter.
그는 대단했어
사람들은 그를 어둠의 왕자라고 했어
I watched him conjure up Lucifer in my
home. He was deeper in it than me.
자니는 영혼을 팔아서
많은 걸 얻어 구해내려 한거야
He made a pact with Satan.
He sold his soul.
거짓말 말라고 했잖아...
자니의 명성은 정당한거야
고대의 원고대로야
You expect me to swallow that?
- I don't give a damn!
그에겐 희생자가 필요했어
그의 나이와 같은 자야
That's a crock of shit,
you lying toad!
- 왜?
- 영혼을 빼앗기 위해서야
그래서 푸츠는
젊은 군인을 고른 거야
He sold his soul for stardom.
- For stardom?
누구지?
타임 스퀘어에
새해 축제를 하던 젊은 군인이야
Satan rose from the depths.
그 군인이 누구야?
But he tried to outwit
the Prince of Darkness.
그들은 그를 자니의 호텔로 데려가서
의식을 거행하기 시작했어
When he made it big,
he tried to duck out of it.
무슨 의식?
그 젊은이를 고무 매트에
벌거벗겨 눕히고...
That's a crock of shit!
완벽하게 양초와 그리그로
고대의식을 재현 한거야
Johnny found an obscure rite in an
ancient manuscript. He needed a victim.
주변에 5각형을 형성하는 거지
마가렛은 자니의 순결을
얻기 위한 거야
Someone his own age. - Why?
- To steal their soul.
그리고 그를 가르고
심장을 꺼내서 먹었어
Toots and Johnny
picked up a young soldier.
그의 재빠른 솜씨에
심장은 아직도 뛰고 있었어
Who?
- Just a soldier
celebrating New Year's Eve in New York.
자니는 누구였던 건 간에
새로이 그 병사가 된거야
They took him back to Johnny's hotel,
where they had the ceremony.
하지만 그가 일을 시작하기도 전에
군에 징병이 됐어
What ceremony?
그가 부상당해 돌아왔을 땐
이미 자신이 누군지 모르게 된거야
The boy was bound naked on a rubber mat,
there were complicated incantations.
- 그 군인이 누구야?
- 자니만이 알뿐이야
A pentacle was branded on his chest.
그는 군번줄을 마가렛의
화병 속에 넣어두었어
Margaret gave Johnny a virgin dagger.
He sliced the boy clean open
and ate his heart.
그건 그가 타임 스퀘어에 들렸던
마가렛이 있던 곳에 있어
그가 기억이 있을 때
마지막으로 들렸던 장소야
It was still beating
when he wolfed it down.
Johnny wanted to become that soldier.
그는 희생자가 필요했어
자신의 나이와 같은
Before he had worked it out,
he was drafted,
injured and sent home
without even knowing who he was.
그들 영혼을 빼앗는 거야
Who was the boy?
그리고 그를 가르고
심장을 꺼내서 먹었어
Only Johnny knew. He put the dog tags
in a vase and gave it to Margaret.
그자가 누구야?
It was Margaret's plan
to drop him off in Times Square.
자니는 누구였던 건 간에
새로이 그 병사가 된거야
The last place he remembered
before it happened.
어쩌면 게임은 그 자의 영혼속에
소유됐을지 몰라
그는 아직도
자니란 이름으로 보일 테니까
He needed a victim.
Someone his own age.
To steal their soul.
He sliced the boy clean open
and he ate his heart.
Who was the boy?
Johnny wanted to be the soldier.
Maybe he gained the guy's soul,
but he still looked like Johnny to me.
난 내가 누군지 알아
누군지 알아
물론 나야
알라스
I know who I am!
현명해서 이득을 얻지 못할 때
지혜란 얼마나 끔찍한가, 자니
루이스 사이퍼
루시퍼
순진한척한 시간은 농담이었어
메피스토펠레스는 맨해튼에선
자네 입을 닥치게 했어, 자니
Alas . . .
당신은 그 악마란 게...
미신을 믿는
늙은 기타 주자나 겁을 주고...
How terrible is wisdom if it brings
no profit to the wise, Johnny.
마녀와 당신의
더러운 인간 따위로...
Louis Cyphre . . .
날 겁 줄 수 있을 거라 생각했소?
난...
난 내가 누군지 알아
"Lucifer!"
당신이 죽였어
내게 뒤집어 씌운 거야
Even your name is a dime store joke.
"Mephistopheles" is
such a mouthful in Manhattan, Johnny.
난 내가 누군지 알아
냉정히 따져보면
자네가 더욱 의심받을 텐데?
Do you think posing as the devil,
just because it scared
a superstitious old guitar player,
당신은 미쳤어
난 내가 누군지 알아
and that witch,
and that nutty old man,
당신은 날 겁주는 거야
사이퍼, 난 내가 누군지 알아
do you think it's going to scare me?
It ain't, because I know who I am.
당신이 사람들을 죽였어
난 절대 누구도 안 죽였어
You killed them,
and you're trying to pin it on me.
난 파울러를 죽이지 않았어
난 투츠를 죽이지 않았어
I know who I am.
If I had cloven hooves and a tail,
would you be more convinced?
난 마가렛을 죽이지 않았어
난 크루즈마크를 죽이지 않았어
난 아무도 죽이지 않았어
You're crazy.
- 자네 짓이야, 자니
- 내 이름은 자니가 아냐
I know who I am.
You're trying to frame me.
모두 자네 손으로 죽였어
당연히 인도는 내가 했지
I know who I am. You murdered them
people! I never killed nobody!
솔직히...
자넨 젊은 병사를 가르는 순간
자니가 된거야
I didn't kill Fowler,
12년간 자넨 다른 자의
기억 속에 살아왔던 거야
I didn't kill Toots,
and I didn't kill Margaret or Krusemark.
이봐요, 와인셉과 얘기하겠소
그가 모든 걸 알테니...
I killed no one.
I'm afraid you did, Johnny.
- My name's not Johnny!
와인셉? 그는 죽었어
끔찍한 사고로
All killed by your own hand.
Guided by me, naturally.
걱정 말게. 누구도 세상에
변호사가 적다곤 안할 테니까
You were doomed from the moment
you slit that young boy in half.
어디건 죽음은 널려있어, 자니
You've been living on borrowed time and
another man's memories for 1 2 years.
하지만 인간의 목숨이 가치가 있나?
아무튼...
누구를 사랑하거나 증오하지
육신은 나약해, 자니
오직 영혼만이 강해
I want to tell Winesap, he knows!
- He's dead.
Nasty accident!
Don't worry, no one will mourn one less
lawyer. Death's everywhere these days.
넌 내게 속해있었어
But what gives
human life its worth, anyway?
난 내가 누군지 알아
Because someone loves it, hates it.
그거야, 자니 잘 보라구
The flesh is weak.
Only the soul is immortal.
아무튼 영리하다면 거울에 비친
자신의 모습을 잘 보라구
눈을 똑바로 뜨고 말야
난 내가 누군지 알아
And yours belongs to me!
I know who I am.
That's it Johnny, take a good look!
However cleverly you
sneak up on the mirror, your reflection
always looks you straight in the eye.
- I know who I am.
난 내가 누군지 알아!
I know who I am!
왜 돌아왔지?
난 여기서 살아
누구지?
엔젤 해롤드로군
Why did you come back?
그녀는 내 딸이오
거짓말
누구지?
에피파니 프라우드풋
잠시 여기서 머무른 거요
I live here.
Who is she?
충분히 살해할만 하군, 그렇지?
최소한 가랑이를 자르지 않았다 해도 말야
She ain't: Angel, Harold.
She's my daughter.
Bullshit! Who is she?
Epiphany Proudfoot.
She stayed here for a little while.
이번 대가를 치러야 할걸세, 엔젤
Long enough for you to kill her?
Or ain't that your gun up her snatch?
알아요
You're going to burn for this.
I know.
In hell!